（ベルベット）がああっ！
（ベルベット）
あの日から 世界は変わった
From that day forward, the world changed.
It became a hell where humans and beasts, possessed by demons, feasted on people.
魔物に憑(つ)かれた人や獣が
人間を食い殺す地獄に
My heart was frozen from despair and hopelessness.
絶望に凍りついた
私の心が感じるのは―
血まみれの肉の味と―
All it knew was the taste of bloodied flesh...
and hatred for one man.
あの男への憎悪だけだ
あの男は どこにいる
Where is he?
You've fed on daemons and persevered in this darkness for many years.
業魔(ごうま)を喰(く)らい こんな暗闇で
何年も耐え忍んできた
Do you hate him that much,
それほどまでに
あの方が憎いのですか？
Velvet Crowe?
ベルベット･クラウ
What's his malak doing here?
（ベルベット）
あの男の聖隷(せいれい)が 何を…
Where is Artorius?!
アルトリウスは どこにいる！
You must hurry.
（シアリーズ）急ぎなさい
ここに来るまで いくつもの
頸木(くびき)を破ってきました
I broke through several barriers in order to get here.
The exorcists have surely noticed.
（シアリーズ）
対魔士なら 気づいて当然
If you wish to leave this place, there's no time to waste.
ここを出たいのなら
猶予はありません
（ベルベット）ふんっ
Praetor exorcists!
二等対魔士です
（対魔士１）うっ ぐあっ！
ええいっ
（対魔士たち）ああっ
（ベルベット）どけ
Out of my way.
You are a daemon-eater.
You cannot defeat an exorcist.
喰魔(くうま)のあなたでは
対魔士には勝てない
（対魔士３）はあっ！ うっ…
（ベルベット）うっ！
（対魔士３）うあっ！
（ベルベット）ふっ！
（対魔士４）おっ…
Velvet!
（シアリーズ）ベルベット！
（ベルベット）ぐっ… うっ
（シアリーズ）こっちです
This way!
どうして？
What?
何のつもりですか？
What are you doing?
The barriers you broke through are this way, right?
（ベルベット）あんたが
結界を破ってきたルートでしょ？
We'll go back there. I'm not stupid.
そこに戻る
バカじゃない
And here I thought you only knew how to charge headfirst into battle.
（シアリーズ）突進だけが―
あなたの戦い方かと
思っていましたが―
違うようですね
It seems I was mistaken.
Surprised I chose to hide here instead?
（ベルベット）
この部屋に 身を隠したこと？
Yes.
Artorius is my only goal.
（ベルベット）
目的は アルトリウスだけだ
そのために利用できるものは
何でも利用する
I'll do whatever it takes to get to him.
This is useless.
使えない
This must be where they store what they've confiscated from the daemons.
ここは 業魔から没収した品が
保管してあるようですね
（シアリーズ）
その太刀は “號嵐(ごうらん)”？
That is a Tempest Blade!
なぜ こんなところに
What's it doing in a place like this?
私には大きすぎるか
It might be too big for me.
Are you sure? The Tempest Blade is a fine sword.
いいのですか？
號嵐は 希代の名刀ですが
（ベルベット）
どんなに すごくても―
It doesn't matter how great it is if I can't use it.
使いこなせなきゃ 意味がない
Many things have happened since your imprisonment here three years ago.
あなたが ここに収監されてから
３年という間―
世界が変わる
様々なことが起きました
The world has changed a great deal.
Don't you want to know what's happened?
何が起こったか
知りたくないのですか？
今 世界には
多数の対魔士が存在し―
The exorcists are many now, and they're
organizing a resistance against the daemons.
組織立って 業魔に対抗を
Tell me.
（ベルベット）言え
Where is Artorius?
アルトリウスは どこだ
In Logress, the royal capital in the sacred kingdom of Midgand.
ミッドガンド領にある 王都
ローグレスにいらっしゃいます
There may be exorcists standing ready outside.
対魔士が 表に
大挙しているかもしれませんよ
Are you sure you don't want to know?
本当に 知らなくてよいのですか？
You aren't curious about what you saw that night?
あの夜 見たものが 何なのか
That night...
あの夜
あの方が成された儀式を境に―
The ritual he performed changed the world.
世界は変わりました
多数の聖隷が降臨し―
Many malakim descended.
それを従えた対魔士たちが
業魔の氾濫(はんらん)を食い止めたのです
And the exorcists they obeyed stopped the flood of daemons.
As the leader of the Abbey,
the organization of exorcists,
今や 対魔士の組織
“聖寮(せいりょう)”を率いる あの方は―
王国からも 民衆からも
絶大な信頼を得ています
he has earned the trust of both the kingdom and its people.
He is the people's shield,
the sword that hunts daemons.
人を守る“盾”にして
業魔を狩る“剣(つるぎ)”
救世主 アルトリウス･
コールブランドとして
Artorius Collbrande is now hailed as their savior.
あの子を犠牲にして
得た力でしょ
He acquired his power by sacrificing a child.
（シアリーズ）
ですが まだ完全ではありません
Yes, but he is not yet complete.
He can still be killed.
今なら 殺すことができます
あんただって その１人でしょ
I thought you were one of the malakim that followed him...
Seres.
聖隷 シアリーズ
I was.
無論
（ベルベット）
そのあんたが なぜ？
So what happened?
理由は 無事に脱獄できたら
お話しします
I will tell you after we escape from this place.
（ベルベット）フゥ…
Listen carefully to what I say.
（ロクロウ）
俺の言うことを よく聞けよ
さもなくば…
Or else.
（ベルベット）フッ フフフフ…
（ロクロウ）何がおかしい？
What's so funny?
You sure are unlucky.
（ベルベット）
ツイてないのね あんた
What?
（ロクロウ）何だと？
You're trying to break out, aren't you?
あんた 脱獄者でしょ
An escapee trying to break out by taking another escapee hostage?
（ベルベット）脱獄者が 脱獄者を
間違って捕まえるなんて―
Talk about irony.
ツイてなさすぎる
（ロクロウ）あ… じゃあ お前…
Then you're...
脱獄者よ
The same as you.
対魔士が 至るところに
うろうろしてやがると思ったら
No wonder the place is crawling with exorcists.
ハァ… そういうことだったのか
So you're the reason!
（シアリーズ）あ… この者は―
This man is a daemon!
業魔！
なるほど
I see.
You two aren't your average humans either.
お前たちも ただの人間って
わけじゃなさそうだな
さーて 行くか
Oh, well. So long.
There could be hordes of exorcists waiting outside.
表は 対魔士だらけかも
しれませんよ
I have to find my partner before I get out of here.
脱獄の前に 相棒を
見つけないといけないんでな
まーた 看守をとっつかまえて
手がかりの１つでも…
I'll just snatch a guard and get some information out of him.
おおっ？ それは！
That's it!
ええいっ
號嵐！
Tempest Blade!
That's my partner!
それが 俺の相棒だ！
これが あんたの？
This is your partner?
いや 今は 私のものよ
Well, it's mine now.
號嵐で 冗談を聞く余裕
多くはないぞ
I don't mess around when it comes to my Tempest Blade.
なら こいつで試してみる？
We'll see about that.
お前… ふんっ
You...
１つ 聞く
Just one question.
あんた こいつを使いこなせるの？
Can you use this thing?
当然 俺の相棒だ
Of course. It's my partner, after all.
Can you defeat exorcists with it?
対魔士を倒すことも？
（ロクロウ）
フッ 対魔士ごとき―
Don't make me laugh.
This dull dagger I stole is more than enough for the likes of them.
やつらから奪った
このナマクラで十分
All right.
分かった
I'll give this back to you.
この號嵐を あんたに渡そう
ただし 条件がある
On one condition.
What?
（ロクロウ）条件？
で どうすりゃいい？
So what do you want me to do?
（ベルベット）
船の用意は どうなってる？
Do you have a ship ready?
ここが島だと
ご存じだったのですね
So you knew you were on an island.
Yes.
ええ 業魔を収監した
監獄島ってことも
I know this is a prison island where daemons are held.
私のエサが
命乞いしながら 教えてくれたわ
My prey told me as they begged for their lives.
There are two ports, one on each side of the island.
港は 島の表と裏に １つずつ
My ship is on the back side.
私の船は
島の裏手につけてあります
What are the chances there'll be exorcists waiting for us there?
（ベルベット）そこに
対魔士が待ち構えている可能性は？
この状況であれば
いると考えるのが自然
Given the current situation,
we should assume the worst.
If I was in charge, I'd send all the ships out to sea to trap us here.
私なら 港から
全ての船を出して―
この島に閉じ込める
そうなれば 私は
ここから出ることはできない
That way, there'd be no way for us to escape.
Then what should we do?
なら こっちのやることは―
I say we whittle down their forces.
やつらの戦力を削(そ)ぎ―
そして 力ずくで
船を奪える状況を作る
That'll make it easier for me to take a ship by force.
それで
俺と こいつってわけだな
And that's where my partner and I come in.
（ベルベット）この監獄島について
私が分かることは 多くない
I don't know much about this prison.
私のいた 地下の階層のこと
I only know that I was held in the underground level
その上の層に―
and that approximately one thousand daemons were in the level above me.
おそらく 1,000に近い業魔を
収監していること
（シアリーズ）どうして それを？
How did you find out?
（ベルベット）私が 日々
どれだけの業魔を―
Would you like to know how many daemons I was forced to fight each day?
喰わされていたか 聞きたいか？
この層が 独房層であることは
２人の話からも間違いない
Judging from what you told me,
this level contains individual cells.
So...
で あれば
牢獄から囚人たちを解き放って―
We'll release all the prisoners and create a riot.
混乱を作る
（シアリーズ）
船を出す隙を与えないわけですね
You won't give them a chance to send the ships out to sea.
（ベルベット）いいわね？
（シアリーズ）ええ
Sound good?
Yes.
Now you just have to separate and whittle down the enemy forces as much as possible.
（ベルベット）あとは できるだけ
敵の戦力の削減と分散を
I'm a man of my word.
約束は守ろう
I figured you'd be the type to thrive in chaos.
あんたには
混乱が似合いそうなんでな
（ベルベット）はああっ！
（ロクロウ）破(は)っ！
He's strong.
（ベルベット）強い
（ロクロウ）ハァ…
これしきで刃こぼれするか
This is all it took to bring them down?
こいつは 本当にナマクラだな
It's really dull too.
俺は かまわねえぜ
始めてくれ
I'm good to go.
You can start any time.
（ベルベット）シアリーズ
Seres!
（ロクロウ）
この先の突き当たりを 右に行け
Turn right at the end of this corridor.
That's the route to the upper level.
上層階に行けるルートだ
こいつの礼だ
That's for giving this back to me.
うっひょー！
引き返しましょう
We must turn back.
あなたの能力は
喰魔としての捕食に限られています
As a daemon-eater, your powers are limited to devouring.
この高さから飛び下りれば
まず 助からない
You won't survive a fall from this height.
I didn't expect them so soon.
思ったより早い
They're exorcists. I won't be able to hold them for long.
相手も対魔士
そんなに時間は稼げません
（ベルベット）
あの子が落とされた祠(ほこら)ほどじゃない
It's not as high as the shrine
where that child was dropped.
ハァ… ハァ… うぐっ
くうっ… ぐっ…
Are you that determined?
（シアリーズ）
あなたは これほどまで…
ハァ…
強いのですね
You are strong.
まるで“誓約”のよう
Almost as if you've forged an oath.
誓約？
What?
（シアリーズ）
自身の言動に枷(かせ)をかけて―
By upholding an oath that restrains your words and actions, you may obtain extraordinary powers.
特別な力を得る儀式のことです
The more restraints you put on yourself, the greater the power you may wield.
厳しい枷で縛るほど
強い力が手に入る
その誓いは ある意味…
In a way, such an oath is...
A curse.
呪いね
行くぞ
Let's go.
That banner...
（シアリーズ）
あの旗は 一等対魔士の証し
It's the crest of Legate exorcists.
Then he must be aboard that ship.
では あの船には…
Artorius...
アルトリウス
You would go that far?
あなたは ここまでして…
（シアリーズ）
あなたの そして 私の旅は―
Your journey, and mine, is about to become even more difficult.
より 困難を迎えそうです
一等対魔士の力は―
Praetor exorcists are nothing
compared to Legate exorcists.
二等対魔士などとは
比較になりません
Knowing this, will you still fight?
それでも戦って 前に進みますか？
（ベルベット）聞くまでもない
That goes without saying.
（シアリーズ）あの男によって
あなたに生まれた感情が―
The raw emotions that this man has evoked in you...
この世界にとって 希望を呼ぶのか
Will they bring hope to this world?
それとも 穢(けが)れをまき散らすのか
Or will they spread malevolence?
それは 未来でクロスする
Those two possibilities will cross in the future.
Don't say anything, just embody the white
We'll show them we can survive, constantly adapting
Blackness, darkness, I cast it all off
I'm already sick of it
Please, give me one last chance
I wanna be white, white, now
With your bared white, with your bared voice
Keep repainting the world into an ideal one
Seek the white, seek the white
It's time for evolution
I wanna be the white, white light
There's no such thing as "right", no such thing as "wrong"
Keep repainting the world into an ideal one
Stain the white, stain the white
It won't stain no matter how hard you try
I wanna be the white, white light
Next Time
No road is long with good company. Travel is harsh and difficult.
Rokurou
This is fate, so let's be friends until we make our escape.
I don't care to be friends.
Velvet
How cold. Once we get off this island, I'll buy you a drink.
Rokurou
...
Velvet
Never mind!
Rokurou
We'll be facing Legate exorcists. Be on your guard.
Seres
Yeah, yeah.
Rokurou
Legate exorcists aren't my concern. My goal is to defeat Artorius.
Velvet
I will have my revenge!
That's the spirit.
Seres
I'll help however I can.
Let's all get out of here!
Rokurou
Yes.
Seres
Yeah.
Velvet
Next week: "Velvet Crowe."
Don't miss it.
Velvet
So it's just gonna be about you?
Rokurou
Aren't you curious?
Velvet
I'd bet the dramatic life story of Rokurou Rangetsu is much more interesting!
Rokurou
Hearing it will bring you to tears.
Telling it brings ME to tears!
Rokurou